Andrés Márquez (C2 English - Native Spanish)

andresmarquez@gmail.com | +(57)-300-612-9066 | Colombia https://www.linkedin.com/in/andresmarquez/ | https://github.com/andresmarquex/

ABOUT ME

Highly motivated and versatile Systems Engineer with over ten years of experience in the areas of system administration, design, implementation & support of Windows Server Systems, and networking. Skilled are not limited only to data development and analysis but also proficiency in web development and technology analysis. Known for problem-solving prowess, data-driven decision-making, and a strong analytical mindset. Combining the strengths of a developer, technology analyst, and web developer, I bridge the gap between data and user-friendly applications for comprehensive data solutions. Possess good communication skills, attention to detail, and the ability to work in a fast-paced environment. Seeking a challenging position in a fast-paced environment that will allow me to contribute my skills and experience to the overall success of your organization.

EDUCATION:

UPB Universidad Pontificia Bolivariana	Feb - 2013
Systems Engineer	Medellin, CO
Universidad de Medellin	Apr - 2012
Business Intelligence (Duration: 1800 hours)	Medellin, CO
UPB Universidad Pontificia Bolivariana	June 2008
Web Development - (Duration: 600 hours)	Medellin, CO
UPB Universidad Pontificia Bolivariana	Dic 2005
Cybersecurity - (Duration: 650 hours)	Medellin, CO

All Certifications Content:

- FrontEnd: Javascript, HTML, CSS
- BackEnd: NodeJS, Python
- Databases: SQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Oracle
- **BI:** MS-SSAS, MS-SSIS, MS-SSRS, PowerBI
- Others: Git, Github, Postman, Scrum

SOFTWARE EDUCATION EXPERIENCE

- Web page with HTML, JS and CSS
- Backend with Node.js and SPRINGBOOT
- DevOps in AZURE, AWS and GCP

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Fourier Analitcs - https://www.fouriering.com/ (REMOTE)

July 2022 – August 2023

Data Engineer with AWS RS, postgress

• ETL in Python, AWS GLUE

Medellín, CO

Solunion Seguros de Credito - https://www.solunion.co/

July 2021 - June 2022

IT Consultant

Latin America

• Client support - Tier 2

NTT DATA Everis BPO- https://co.nttdata.com/

Jan 2020 – Jun 2021

IT Consultant

Latin America

Client support - Tier 2

Software ONE Intergrupo - https://www.softwareone.com/es-es

Nov 2017 - Aug 2019

• Dynamics CRM developer, functional analyst and tester

Medellín, CO

MORE INFO

• Languages: C2 English & Spanish native

• Other Experience: 10 years in IT support, networking and server administration (WIN-LINUX)

• Other soft skills: 2 years experience as a tech teacher.

LINKS Social Media

• Instagram: https://instagram.com/andresmarquez

• Twitter: https://twitter.com/andresmarquez